Subject Files
Marist Archives and Special Collections
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  - Subject files: Softball (Lowell Thomas, Jr.), 1930s; 5 (Box 1560)
    - [A group of men dressed as women], 5
    - [Taft softball team], 6
    - [Taft softball team sitting on the bleachers], 7
    - John McGovern and Lowell Thomas's Son, Lowell Thomas, Jr. Shall find out what John did for baseball + let you know. He is a prominent N.Y.C. lawyer I believe. You may remember him. [2 copies], 8
    - Verso: John McGovern and Lowell Thomas's Son, Lowell Thomas, Jr. Shall find out what John did for baseball + let you know. He is a prominent N.Y.C. lawyer I believe. You may remember him., 8-verso
    - [A group of young men], 9
  - Subject files: Softball (Gene Tunney), circa 1930s; 6 (Box 1560)
    - (Tunney Batting); Boxer Tunney a Slugger? New Canaan, Conn.Though his form can be described by a word that begins with an "L" and ends with a "Y" (not lovely), retired heavyweight king -- now columnist, Gene Tunney, is shown belting out a clean hit as his Fourth Estate "Connecticut Nutmegs" met commentator Lowell Thomas's "Nine Old Men" in a charity soft ball game yesterday. That's Thomas behind the bat. Note Gene's left foot "in the bucket." It would bring a nervous breakdown for any baseball manager. The Tunney bunch won 10-9, 1
    - Note: (Tunney Batting); Boxer Tunney a Slugger? New Canaan, Conn.Though his form can be described by a word that begins with an "L" and ends with a "Y" (not lovely), retired heavyweight king -- now columnist, Gene Tunney, is shown belting out a clean hit as his Fourth Estate "Connecticut Nutmegs" met commentator Lowell Thomas's "Nine Old Men" in a charity soft ball game yesterday. That's Thomas behind the bat. Note Gene's left foot "in the bucket." It would bring a nervous breakdown for any baseball manager. The Tunney bunch won 10-9, 2
    - Shipley, 3
    - Verso: Shipley, 3-verso
    - [Gene Tunny standing with a man], 4
    - Gene Tunney + L.T., 5
    - Verso: Gene Tunney + L.T., 5-verso
    - [Gene Tunny, Governor Cross, and Lowell Thomas], 6
    - Gene Tunney, L.T. and Gov. Cross the ex-Gov[ernor] of Conn[ecticut] about to throw out the first ball, 7
    - Verso: Gene Tunney, L.T. and Gov. Cross the ex-Gov[ernor] of Conn[ecticut] about to throw out the first ball, 7-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas and Gene Tunny], 8
    - [Lowell Thomas talking to a man, Gene Tunny next to him], 9
    - [Gene Tunny (on right) sitting with two men], 10
    - [Gene Tunny on the pitcher's mound], 11
    - [Gene Tunny getting ready to pitch], 12
    - [Gene Tunny pitching], 13
    - Gene Tunney at bat, 14
    - Verso: Gene Tunney at bat, 14-verso
    - [Gene Tunny talking to a woman], 15
    - [Gene Tunny in a crowd of people], 16
  - Subject files: Softball (Billy Van as President Franklin Delano Roosevelt), undated; 7 (Box 1560)
    - Billy Van with Theodore Roosevelt, Jr., 1
    - Note: Billy Van with Theodore Roosevelt, Jr., 2
    - [Billy Van with Theodore Roosevelt, Jr.], 3
    - [Billy Van with Theodore Roosevelt, Jr.], 4
    - [Billy Van with Theodore Roosevelt, Jr.], 5
    - Gen. Theodore Roosevelt, Billy B. Van, 6
    - Verso: Gen. Theodore Roosevelt, Billy B. Van, 6-verso
    - Vaudeville star Billy Van, famous for his impersonation of F.D.R. On running board of car Gen. Theo. Roosevelt, Jr. crowd at "9 Old Men" game completely taken in by the impersonation. (1940), 7
    - Verso: Vaudeville star Billy Van, famous for his impersonation of F.D.R. On running board of car Gen. Theo. Roosevelt, Jr. crowd at "9 Old Men" game completely taken in by the impersonation. (1940), 7-verso
    - [Billy Van with Theodore Roosevelt, Jr.], 8
    - [Billy Van as F.D.R.], 9
  - Subject files: Softball (Anna Mae Wong), 1937 August; 8 (Box 1560)
    - Players and fans; Anna May Wong, center, Henrick Wilhelm, VanLoon [Hendrik Willem van Loon], right, 1
    - Verso: Players and fans; Anna May Wong, center, Henrick Wilhelm, VanLoon [Hendrik Willem van Loon], right, 1-verso
    - Anna Mae Wong - LT, 2
    - Verso: Anna Mae Wong - LT, 2-verso
    - INSTRUCTIONS TO THE UMPIRE; Poundridge, N.Y. --- Not in the least disturbed by the declaration of umpire Anna May Wong that she "knew less than nothing" about baseball, Lowell, Thomas undertakes to explain the difference between a strike and a ball to the actress before the start of the game between his "Nine Old Men" and George T. Bye's "Prehistoric Sluggers" in Flaucher's Meadows August 15 for the benefit of the local volunteer fire department. Apparently he did a good job, for the "Nine Old Men" won by a score of 15 to 12. Members of both teams were well-known persons from literary and entertainment circles. 0-8/16/37 8, 3
    - Note: INSTRUCTIONS TO THE UMPIRE; Poundridge, N.Y. --- Not in the least disturbed by the declaration of umpire Anna May Wong that she "knew less than nothing" about baseball, Lowell, Thomas undertakes to explain the difference between a strike and a ball to the actress before the start of the game between his "Nine Old Men" and George T. Bye's "Prehistoric Sluggers" in Flaucher's Meadows August 15 for the benefit of the local volunteer fire department. Apparently he did a good job, for the "Nine Old Men" won by a score of 15 to 12. Members of both teams were well-known persons from literary and entertainment circles. 0-8/16/37 8, 4
    - [Anna Mae Wong, umpiring], 5
  - Subject files: Softball (with Lowell Thomas), circa 1930s; 9 (Box 1560)
    - Vilhjalmur Stefansson, famous Arctic explorer, talking over softball strategy with pitcher Sir Hubert Wilkins, during a game on Quaker Hill near Pawling, New York between The Explorers Club Fossils and Lowell Thomas's Nine Old Men, 1
    - Verso: Vilhjalmur Stefansson, famous Arctic explorer, talking over softball strategy with pitcher Sir Hubert Wilkins, during a game on Quaker Hill near Pawling, New York between The Explorers Club Fossils and Lowell Thomas's Nine Old Men, 1-verso
    - [Sir Hubert Wilkins, left, Lowell Thomas, right], 2
    - [Sir Hubert Wilkins, left, Lowell Thomas, right], 3
    - [right to left: Lowell Thomas, Sir Hubert Wilkins, Vilhjalmur Stefansson, 4
    - [right to left: Lowell Thomas, Sir Hubert Wilkins, Vilhjalmur Stefansson, 5
    - for our softball file, probably father and son game [Lowell Thomas, Jr., left, Lowell Thomas, right], 6
    - Note: for our softball file, probably father and son game [Lowell Thomas, Jr., left, Lowell Thomas, right], 7
    - Katherine Cornell rehearsing again? No, Lowell Thomas explaining a fine point about Softball, 8
    - Note: Katherine Cornell rehearsing again? No, Lowell Thomas explaining a fine point about Softball, 9
    - L.T. and Hendrik van Loon [Hendrik Willem van Loon], 10
    - Verso: L.T. and Hendrik van Loon [Hendrik Willem van Loon], 10-verso
    - [L.T. and Hendrik van Loon [Hendrik Willem van Loon]], 11
    - L.T. seated on left, an his famous soft ball teams, 12
    - Verso: L.T. seated on left, an his famous soft ball teams, 12-verso
    - [L.T. seated on left, an his famous soft ball teams], 13
    - [Lowell Thomas sitting with a group of women], 14
    - [Lowell Thomas writing something during a softball game], 15
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with a group of softball players], 16
    - [Lowell Thomas sitting with two women], 17
    - [Lowell Thomas sitting with two women], 18
    - L.T. pitching for the 9 Old Men, 19
    - Verso: L.T. pitching for the 9 Old Men, 19-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas on base], 20
    - [Lowell Thomas in his softball uniform], 21
    - L.T. With Captain Richenbacker, 22
    - Verso: L.T. With Captain Richenbacker, 22-verso
    - [Lowell Thoma sstanding with a man in Kodak Park softball uniforms], 23
    - [Lowell Thomas and two men holding up a large fake bat], 24
    - [Lowell Thomas sitting with his softball teammates], 25
    - [Lowell Thomas sitting in a car with a group of other men], 26
    - [Lowell Thomas shaking hands with a man in a cowboy outfit], 27
    - [Man wearing a hat], 28
    - [Man laying in the grass], 29
    - [Outfieldman], 30
    - [Lowell Thomas sitting with men in suits], 31
    - [Lowell Thomas and his friends watching a softball game], 32
  - Subject files: Softball (without Lowell Thomas), circa 1930s; 10 (Box 1560)
    - [Fifi D'Orsay], 1
    - [Theodore Roosevelt, Jr, right], 2
    - [Sir Hubert Wilkins, left], 3
    - [Softball team], 4
    - [Two men walking on the softball field], 5
    - [People watching the softball game], 6
    - [Men sitting on the bleachers], 7
    - [Men on the softball field], 8
    - [Softball players on the field], 9
    - [Nine old men softball team poster], 10
    - [Men sitting on the bleachers], 11
    - [Men watching the softball game], 12
    - [Man dressed as a sailor with a mop], 13
    - [Softball player], 14
    - [Nine Old Men teammate], 15
    - [Pitcher getting ready to throw the ball], 16
    - [Player on the Nine Old Men softball team], 17
    - [A group of people surrounding a car], 18
    - [Man laying on the grass], 19
    - [Softball player], 20
    - [Poster announcing a softball game: Lowell Thomas's Nine Old Men vs. Col. Roosevelt's Oysters], 21
    - [Talley's Movietone Midgets softball team], 22
  - Subject files: Softball (without Lowell Thomas), circa 1930s; 11 (Box 1560)
    - Taken Aug 9 1947 Smith Johnson, 1
    - Verso: Taken Aug 9 1947 Smith Johnson, 1-verso
    - Taken Aug 9 1947 Smith Johnson, 2
    - Verso: Taken Aug 9 1947 Smith Johnson, 2-verso
    - Taken Aug 9 1947 Smith Johnson, 3
    - Verso: Taken Aug 9 1947 Smith Johnson, 3-verso
    - Sir Hubert Wilkins, 4
    - Verso: Sir Hubert Wilkins, 4-verso
    - Les Kramer - Lejaren Hiller - Osa Johnson, J. Allan Dunn, 5
    - Verso: Les Kramer - Lejaren Hiller - Osa Johnson, J. Allan Dunn, 5-verso
    - Explorers club group, 6
    - Verso: Explorers club group, 6-verso
    - Heywood Broun waiting his turn at bat, 7
    - Verso: Heywood Broun waiting his turn at bat, 7-verso
    - Heywood Broun, 8
    - Verso: Heywood Broun, 8-verso
    - Heywood Broun, 9
    - Verso: Heywood Broun, 9-verso
    - Mike Shipley 602 Pine St. Lancaster, PA, 10
    - Verso: Mike Shipley 602 Pine St. Lancaster, PA, 10-verso
    - Explorer Carveth Wells, 11
    - Verso: Explorer Carveth Wells, 11-verso
    - [McClelland Barclay], 12
    - Verso: McClelland Barclay, 12-verso
    - [McClelland Barclay], 13
    - Bud Kelland, 14
    - Verso: Bud Kelland, 14-verso
    - Sir Hubert Wilkins, Hollick Kenyon, [?], 15
    - Verso: Sir Hubert Wilkins, Hollick Kenyon, [?], 15-verso
    - [Napoleon (Les Kramer)], 16
    - [Heywood Broun], 17
    - [Heywood Broun], 18
  - Subject files: Softball (without Lowell Thomas), circa 1930s; 12 (Box 1560)
    - [L to R - Jimmy Doolittle and Frank Hawks to bat with rifle with Doolittle as caddy], 1
    - L to R - Jimmy Doolittle and Frank Hawks to bat with rifle with Doolittle as caddy, 2
    - Verso: L to R - Jimmy Doolittle and Frank Hawks to bat with rifle with Doolittle as caddy, 2-verso
    - Dr. Herbert Spinden - dir. Bklyn Museum, white hair, second row middle; Helen Lanker - Ambas, Wm. Pauley, Lucile Parks, Mrs. Luis Mora, Dr. Shaw Carter- left corner, 3
    - Verso: Dr. Herbert Spinden - dir. Bklyn Museum, white hair, second row middle; Helen Lanker - Ambas, Wm. Pauley, Lucile Parks, Mrs. Luis Mora, Dr. Shaw Carter- left corner, 3-verso
    - [left to right: Westbrook Pegler, Deems Taylor, George Bye, 4
    - [Napoleon (Les Kramer)], 5
    - Les Kramer (Napoleon) [left], Lejaren Hiller, 6
    - Verso: Les Kramer (Napoleon) [left], Lejaren Hiller, 6-verso
    - Sir Hubert Wilkins - Col. Stoopnagle and Col. Ted Roosevelt [Theodore Roosevelt, Jr.] behind him, 7
    - Verso: Sir Hubert Wilkins - Col. Stoopnagle and Col. Ted Roosevelt [Theodore Roosevelt, Jr.] behind him, 7-verso
  - Subject files: Softball (without Lowell Thomas), circa 1930s; 13 (Box 1560)
    - [Two softball players], 1
    - [Children sitting with a dog on a baseball field], 2
    - [Youth softball team], 3
    - [Softball team], 4
    - [Women sitting on the bleachers], 5
    - [Lowell Thomas sitting with a group of young softball players], 6
    - [Men watching the softball game], 7
    - [Men watching the softball game], 8
    - [Spectators at a softball game], 9
    - [Two men drinking Coca-Cola], 10
    - [Three men walking downhill], 11
    - [A group of men standing with a band], 12
    - [Spectators watching a softball game], 13
    - [Softball player], 14
    - [Three men sitting in a car], 15
    - [Man on horse laying on the ground], 16
    - [Cartoon for Lowell Thomas's Nine Old Men softball team], 17
  - Subject files: Softball (miscellaneous), circa 1930s - 1941; 14 (Box 1560)
    - Henry Wallace at bat, June 1941, 1
    - Verso: Henry Wallace at bat, June 1941, 1-verso
    - Nine Old Men versus Teddy Roosevelt, Jr.'s Oysters of Oyster Bay; left to right, sitting, Napoleon (Les Kramer); Author Ted Shane; Captain Lowell Thomas; Umpire "Judge" Emerson Ives; Hillbilly Cartoonist Paul Webb; Attorney Charles Murphy; Standing left to right: Novelist Homer Croy; Colonel Lemuel Q. Stoopnagle (F. Chase Taylor); Billy Van, impersonator of F.D.R.; Graham McNamee; Attorney Bill Spence, 2
    - Note: Nine Old Men versus Teddy Roosevelt, Jr.'s Oysters of Oyster Bay; left to right, sitting, Napoleon (Les Kramer); Author Ted Shane; Captain Lowell Thomas; Umpire "Judge" Emerson Ives; Hillbilly Cartoonist Paul Webb; Attorney Charles Murphy; Standing left to right: Novelist Homer Croy; Colonel Lemuel Q. Stoopnagle (F. Chase Taylor); Billy Van, impersonator of F.D.R.; Graham McNamee; Attorney Bill Spence, 3
    - [Lowell Thomas at a softball game], 4
    - [Lowell Thomas talking to people at a softball game], 5
    - [Lowell Thomas talking to two men], 6
    - [People sitting on the bleachers at a softball game], 7
    - [Spectators sitting on the bleachers at a softball game], 8
    - [Spectators sitting on the bleachers at a softball game], 9
    - [People sitting on bleachers watching a softball game], 10
    - [Softball player up at bat], 11
    - [Man hitting the ball], 12
    - [Man in the outfield], 13
    - [Softball players in the field], 14
    - [Lowell Thomas sitting with a softball team], 15
    - [Spectators watching the softball game], 16
    - [Men standing on the edge of a pool], 17
    - [A group of men standing outside a house], 18
    - [Vehicles used to transport Briggs Manufactuing Company amateur softball team], 19
    - Note: [Letter to Lowell Thomas from Briggs Manufactuing Company concerning proposed softball matchup], 20
  - Subject files: Softball (miscellaneous), circa 1930s; 15 (Box 1560)
    - Colonel Furlong, 1
    - Verso: Colonel Furlong, 1-verso
    - Homer Croy at bat, 2
    - Verso: Homer Croy at bat, 2-verso
    - H. T. Cowling, right, talking to Burton Holmes (two canes), 3
    - Verso: H. T. Cowling, right, talking to Burton Holmes (two canes), 3-verso
    - [Burton Holmes with Osa Johnson], 4
    - Verso: Burton Holmes, 4-verso
    - [Burton Holmes with Osa Johnson], 5
    - [Burton Holmes with Osa Johnson], 6
    - [Burton Holmes with Osa Johnson], 7
    - [Osa Johnson with Les Kramer (Napoleon)], 8
    - [Osa Johnson, center, Lowell Thomas, right], 9
    - [right to left: Lowell Thomas, Osa Johnson], 10
    - [right to left: Lowell Thomas, Osa Johnson], 11
    - [Osa Johnson, right], 12
    - [Osa Johnson with Lowell Thomas (back to camera)], 13
    - [Osa Johnson with Lowell Thomas (back to camera)], 14
    - [Osa Johnson holding The Explorers Club flag], 15
    - [Sir Hubert Wilkins, left], 16
    - [Man swinging a bat], 17
    - [Lowell Thomas talking with two people], 18
    - [Pitcher on the piter's mound], 19
    - [Lowell Thomas signing autographs], 20
    - [Man pitching during a softball game], 21
    - [Men getting water fron the cooler], 22
    - Two men walking on the softball field], 23
    - [Lowell Thomas signing autographs], 24
    - [People getting food], 25
    - [Man in the outfield], 26
    - [Lowell Thomas signing a book], 27
    - [Man hitting the softball], 28
    - [Man pitching], 29
    - [Lowell Thomas signing his book], 30
    - [Lowell Thomas running to home plate], 31
    - [Lowell Thomas autoraphing his book], 32
    - [Lowell Thomas signing his book], 33
    - [Lowell Thomas giving a man his autograph], 34
    - [Lowell Thomas and a group of people], 35
    - [Lowell Thomas in the background signing his book, two men in costume in the foreground], 36
    - [Spectators watching the softball game], 37
    - [Lowell Thomas eating ice cream with his wife, Frances Ryan Thomas, and two others.], 38
    - [Lowell Thomas autographing his book], 39
    - [Lowell Thomas signing his book], 40
    - [Lowell Thomas signing his book], 41
  - Subject files: Softball (miscellaneous), circa 1930s; 16 (Box 1560)
    - [three photographs were formerly mounted a single frame], [left photograph], 1
    - Verso: Left, 1-verso
    - [three photographs were formerly mounted a single frame], [center photograph], 2
    - Verso: Middle, 2-verso
    - [three photographs were formerly mounted a single frame], [right photograph], 3
    - Verso: Right, 3-verso
  - Subject files: Softball (miscellaneous), 1951 October; 17 (Box 1560)
    - Note: Nine Old Men versus James Melton, 1
    - [Nine Old Men softball team], 2
    - [Nine Old Men softball team on the field], 3
    - [A crowded softball field], 4
    - [An automobile], 5
    - [Cars lined up on thr edge of a softball field], 6
    - [Man standing and pointing], 7
  - Subject files: Softball (miscellaneous), 1962; 18 (Box 1560)
    - [Nine Old Men softall trophy established by WPRO, Providence, Rhode Island, in honor of Lowell Thomas's former team], 1
    - Note: [Letter to Lowell Thomas from WPRO Vice President Joseph P. Dougherty concerning trophy and broadcast of game], 2
  - Subject files: South America, 1935; 19 (Box 1560)
    - [Aerial view of a city in South America], 1
    - [Man standing in a waterfall in South America], 2
  - Subject files: South America trip, 1972; 20 (Box 1560)
    - [Lowell Thomas talking to a man during his South America Trip], 1
    - [Lowell Thomas talking to a man during his South America Trip], 2
    - [A snow-capped mountain over a city in South America], 3
    - [Airplane in South America], 4
    - [People lookingat an airplane in South America], 5
    - [Man sitting in an airplane in South America], 6
  - Subject files: South Pole (second visit returning via Russia), circa 1963; 21 (Box 1560)
    - Note: Returning from Antarctica - Russia, Asia, 1
    - 2-Hy T[?]auac Aireaia[?] aiu Cuhuy Kozo C.U. [?] Moekba [signed], 2
    - Verso: 2-Hy T[?]auac Aireaia[?] aiu Cuhuy Kozo C.U. [?] Moekba [signed], 2-verso
    - Caption: 2-Hy T[?]auac Aireaia[?] aiu Cuhuy Kozo C.U. [?] Moekba [signed], 3
    - Caption: 2-Hy T[?]auac Aireaia[?] aiu Cuhuy Kozo C.U. [?] Moekba [signed], 4
  Box 1561 - Box 1565
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6